Guide to the Lloyd A. Fallers Papers 1937-1977
University of Chicago Library
- Series II: Correspondence
  - Rahman, Fazlur, 1970-1972 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Redfield, James M., 1965-1968 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Reining, Conrad C., 1970 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Rheinstein, Max, 1961 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Richards, Audrey I., 1957-1973 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1958-1972 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Rodemann, H. William, 1960-1962 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Rosberg, Carl G., n.d. (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Rosen, Charles, 1968-1969 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Rosen, Lawrence, 1967-1974 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Rowe, J. H., 1957-1959 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Royal Anthropological Institute, 1966-1968 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Ruel, Malcom, 1959-1971 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - S, general, 1958-1974 (Box 13, Folder 1-2)
  - Saberwal, Satish C., 1962-1966 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Salovesh, Michael, 1965-1973 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Salzman, Philip C., 1967-1973 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Sangree, Walter, 1959-1974 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Scheinfeld, Daniel R., 1959-1973 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Schlegel, Stuart A., 1965-1973 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Schneider, David M., 1959-1969 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Schneider, Harold K., 1966-1967 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Sertel, Ayse K., 1966-1970 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Shepardson, Mary, 1958-1972 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Shibli, Khalid, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Shack, William A., 1959-1971 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Shils, Edward, 1959-1974 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Shorter, Frederic C., 1966-1969 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Sider, Gerald, 1964-1967 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Sills, David L., 1962-1971 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Sluiter, Greet, 1958-1960 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Smith, M. G., n.d. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Social Anthropology, 1960-1962 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Social Science Research Council, 1958-1973 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - South and Southeast Asia, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Southall, Aidan W., 1957-1973 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Southwold, Martin, 1957-1969 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Spoehr, Alexander, 1968-1972 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Stanford University Press, 1959-1968 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Starr, June, 1965-1967 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Strodtbeck, Fred L., 1970 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Sutton, Francis X., 1959-1973 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Suzuki, Peter T., 1969 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Sytek, William, 1964-1965 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - T, general, 1958-1972 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Tanner, Nancy, 1968-1973 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Tax, Sol, 1957-1974 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Thomas, Joseph, 1970-1971 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Thrupp, Sylvia, 1958-1967 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Twinning, W. L., 1969 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - U, general, 1959-1973 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - United States, Department of State, 1958-1969 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - United States, Embassy, Ankara, Turkey, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - United States, Senate, 1969-1971 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - University of Chicago, 1959-1973 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - University of Chicago, Center for the Study of Man in Turkey, correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - University of Chicago, Chicago Maroon, 1964-1973 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - University of Chicago, Committee for the Comparative Study of New Nations, memoranda, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - University of Chicago, Committee for the Comparative Study of New Nations, memoranda, minutes, manuscripts, 1966-1968 (Box 15, Folder 13-15)
  - University of Chicago, Committee on African Studies, correspondence, memoranda, minutes, 1965-1969 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - University of Chicago, Deanship Committee, faculty of the Division of the Social Sciences, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - University of Chicago, Department of Anthropology, memoranda, correspondence, 1964-1969 (Box 16, Folder 1-5)
  - University of Chicago, faculty discussion on "The University, " correspondence, memoranda, minutes, reprints, 1964-1965 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - University of Chicago, student protests, manuscripts, memoranda, correspondence, newspapers, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - University of Chicago Press, 1958-1973 (Box 16, Folder 8-9)
  - University of East Africa, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - University of Rochester, 1962-1967 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - V, general, 1957-1967 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Vilakazi, Absolom L., 1971 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Vinogradov, Amal, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Vowles, Paul F., 1958 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - W, general, 1958-1973 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Warner, David R., n.d. (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Warner, Mildred, 1971-1974 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Weissleder, Wolfgang, 1955-1971 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Welt, Carol, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Wenner-Gren Foundation, 1971-1974 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - White, H., 1960 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Willis, John, 1964-1972 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Willner, Dorothy, 1964-1973 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Wilson, John T., 1969-1971 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Winans, Edgar, 1959-1960 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Winter, Edward H., 1958-1963 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Winzeler, Robert L., 1964-1970 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - World Affairs Council of Northern California, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Y, general, 1965-1972 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Yalmon, Nur, 1961-1971 (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Z, general, 1969-1973 (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Unidentified, general, 1959-1971 (Box 17, Folder 24)
- Series III: Course Materials
  Series III, Course Materials (Boxes 18 to 22), is organized chronologically into subseries following the sequence of Fallers' institutional affiliations and, within each subseries, alphabetically according to subject and course number. Included are papers and notes which Fallers wrote while a student at the University of Chicago (1945-1949), and his lecture notes and syllabi for the courses that he taught at Princeton University (1953-1954), at the University of California, Berkeley (1957-1960), and at the University of Chicago (1960-1974).
  - Subseries 1: Student Notes
    - Anthropology 230B, "Some Similarities and Differences in Polynesia, " class paper by Fallers, 1948 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Anthropology 240 A/B/C, Culture, Society, and the Individual, University of Chicago, syllabi, 1951-1953 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Anthropology 359, History of the Study of Social Organization, Fred Eggan, class notes, 1948 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - "An Analysis of a Case of Long-Term Culture Change, " class paper by Fallers, 1948 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Shils, Edward, class notes, 1947 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 2: Princeton University
    - Sociology 320, Social Disorganization, syllabus, lectures, 1952-1954 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Sociology 322, Criminology, syllabus, lectures, 1954 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 3: University of California, Berkeley
    - Anthropology 123, Law and Politics in Non-Industrial Societies, syllabus, lectures, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Anthropology 124, J. Hitchcock, course outline, 1958 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Anthropology 125, Comparative Society 2, reading list, 1958 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Anthropology 139, Africa, syllabus, examination, 1957-1958 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Anthropology 160, Contemporary Civilization, syllabus, lectures, examination, 1957-1958 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Anthropology 201, K. Davis and D. Schneider, reading list, 1959 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Anthropology 210, Patrimonial Political Systems, reading list, lectures, 1958 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Anthropology 230, East African Ethnology, lectures, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Sociology 217, History of Social Thought since the Enlightenment, syllabus, lectures, 1959-1960 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 4: University of Chicago
    - Anthropology 210, Introduction to Cultural Anthropology, syllabi, lectures, 1963-1965 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Anthropology 230, Ethnological Theory and Method, handouts, lectures, 1959-1960 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Anthropology 235, Peoples of Africa, syllabus, 1961 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Anthropology 260, History and Philosophy of the Social Sciences, syllabus, 1970 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Anthropology 262, Cities and Civilizations, syllabus, handouts, 1961 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Anthropology 310/Sociology 322, Social and Cultural Systems, syllabus, lectures, examinations, 1970-1974 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Anthropology 311/Law 517/Sociology 308, Law in Society and Culture, syllabus, correspondence, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Anthropology 335/History 205, Peoples of Africa, syllabi, lectures, handouts, 1962-1968 (Box 19, Folder 9-11)
    - Anthropology 335/History 205, Peoples of Africa, syllabi (Box 20, Folder 1-2)
    - Anthropology 340/341, Systems, syllabi, lectures, 1963-1964 (Box 20, Folder 3-4)
    - Theoretical Foundations of Anthropology, syllabus, handouts, 1969-1972 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Anthropology 354/454/Sociology 311, Modern Society and Culture, syllabi, lectures, 1960-1967 (Box 20, Folder 6-7)
    - Anthropology 442, Comparison of Cultures, syllabus, handouts, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Anthropology 448, Analysis of Social and Cultural Change, syllabus, 1962 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Anthropology 453, Introduction to Social Anthropology in the Near East, reading list, 1964 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Anthropology 542, lectures, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Law 587, Seminar on Legal Problems in the New Nations in Africa, background papers, photographs, 1962 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Social Sciences 225, examination, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Sociology 206, History and Theory of the Social Sciences, syllabus, lectures, 1973 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Sociology 332/Anthropology 310, Social and Cultural Systems, syllabus lectures, 1974 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - General anthropology examinations, 1960-1963 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Examination, 1966 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Course grade reports, 1972-1973 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - "An Introductory Syllabus on African Anthropology, "n.d. (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Student paper, independent research, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - History of Soc-Cult Thought, tentative syllabus, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Peasant Stratification, lectures, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Lectures, anthropology survey course, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 13-14)
    - Lectures, bureaucracy, n.d (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Lectures, history, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Lectures, history of anthropology, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Lectures, politics and law, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Lectures, miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 5)
- Series IV: Manuscripts by Fallers
  Series IV, (Boxes 22 to 24), contains Fallers' unpublished general manuscripts and lectures arranged alphabetically by title. This series includes his A.M. thesis (1949) and contains a number of lectures in which he examines the relationship of academe to the Christian church.
  - Tribe and Nations, " notes, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - African Christianity, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - African politics, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - "An Anthropologist's Appreciation of Max Weber, "n.d. (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Discipline or Social Club?" Kroeber Society Meeting, May 16, 1959 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - "Anthropology and Political Science, "n.d. (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - "Anthropology in World History, "n.d. (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Book notes, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - "British Social Anthropology and the Study of Culture, "n.d. (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - "The British vs. the French Impact on Africa, "n.d. (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Buganda politics and land, lecture, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - "Cultural and Social Differentiation/Integration, " notes, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - "Customary Law in Present Day Busoga, " notes, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - "Development of Democracy in Non-Western Areas, " notes, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - "Education in the United States, "n.d. (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - "Elite Slaves, "n.d. (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - "Evolution, History and Modernity, "n.d. (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - "Family, " notes, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - "Fieldwork Seminar, " notes, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - "Foreign Policy Under a New Administration, "n.d. (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - "A Frame of Reference for the Study of Authority in Situations of Westernization, "n.d. (Box 22, Folder 26)
  - "The Impact of Technology upon Traditional Cultures, "n.d. (Box 22, Folder 27)
  - "Indigenous Peoples and Cultures of Africa, " Foreign Service Institute, Department of State, February 27, 1961, correspondence, 1960-1961 (Box 22, Folder 28)
  - Inequality, "Preface, " "Introduction, " correspondence, 1973 (Box 22, Folder 29)
  - "Introduction, "n.d. (Box 22, Folder 30)
  - "Introduction to Social Change Seminar, " London School of Economics, 1949-1950 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - "Kinship Structure Seminar, "n.d. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - "Max Weber's Concept of `Traditional Authority', " Clement H. Moore, "Some Comments on Professors Fallers and Weber, " American Political Science Association, annual meeting, New York, September 6-10, 1966 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - "Mission in Africa, "n.d. (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - "Modernity, " notes, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - "Modernization of Buganda, " notes, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - "The Modernization of Social Stratification, "n.d. (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - "Notes on Foreign Policy, especially in Asia and Africa, "1966 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - "Outline of Proposed Paper on the Intellectuals and Politics, " notes, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Politics, notes, 1965-1968 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - "Pre-Colonial East Africa, "n.d. (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - "The Problem of `Tribalism' and African Unity, " Pan-African Students Organization in the Americas, May 11, 1963 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - "Proposed Outline for Study, "n.d. (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - "The Recent Modernization of Asia and Africa in the Context of World History, "n.d. (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - "Response to Incentives in Traditional Agricultural Communities, " African Studies Association, Boston, September 9, 1959 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - "Religion in a University, "n.d. (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - "Religions of East Africa, "n.d. (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - "The Role of Factionalism in Fox Acculturation, " correspondence, 1949, 1970 (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - "Seminar on Processes in Religious Organization, "1959 (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Shoshonean social organization, genealogies, notes, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - "Significance of Max Weber's Work for Socio-Cultural Anthropology, "n.d. (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - Social Anthropology of the Middle East at the University of Chicago, Department seminar, Department of Anthropology, University of Chicago, January 11, 1969 (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - "Social Anthropology and Political Science, " Center for Social Organization Studies, University of Chicago, Working Paper No. 96, November 1, 1967 (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - "Social Class and Social Problems, " notes, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - "Society in Comparative Perspective, " notes, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 25)
  - "Some Problems in the Analysis of Social Change, " notes, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 26)
  - "Some Thoughts on a Theology of the University, "n.d. (Box 23, Folder 27)
  - "The Theory of Signs and the Theory of Social Organization, "1950 (Box 23, Folder 28)
  - "Transferring Technological Innovations, " notes, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 29)
  - "Translating the Faith, "n.d. (Box 23, Folder 30)
  - "Tuesday Club, " lecture, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 31)
  - "Turkey, "n.d. (Box 23, Folder 32)
  - "The United States and the World after Vietnam, " reprint, 1965 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - "Urbanism and Stratification, "n.d. (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - "Why Are East Africans Poor Entrepreneurs, "n.d. (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Elkan, Walter, and Lloyd Fallers, "Labor Mobility and Competing Status Systems, "n.d. (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous, notes, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 5)
- Series V. Manuscripts by Others
  Series V, (Boxes 24 to 27), contains Fallers' collection of manuscripts by other scholars. The material is arranged alphabetically or, if part of a seminar or conference, grouped together under the name of the sponsoring institution. A number of manuscripts by Clifford Geertz are particularly worthy of note.
  - The Anthropology of Law (Syllabus and Bibliography for a Course), " Yale Law School Working Papers in Law and Modernization No. 1, 1971 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - A Case Study of Kenya (Syllabus for a Seminar), " Yale Law School Working Papers in Law and Modernization No. 2, 1971 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Abu-Lughod, Janet, "Migration and Politics in Egypt, "n.d. (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Abu-Zahra, Nadia, "The Impact of the Neo-Destour Party on Tunisian Village Politics, "n.d. (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - A Study in the Accommodation of Tradition, "n.d. (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - A Comparative Analysis, "n.d. (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Bailey, Fredrick. G., "Political Cultures as Cognitive Systems, "n.d. (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Barth, Fredrik, "Economic Spheres in Darfur, "n.d. (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Binder, Leonard, "The Modernization of Egyptian Political Culture, "n.d. (Box 24, Folder 14-15)
  - Perspectives on Middle East Studies, "1973 (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Political Development in Iran, "n.d. (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Binder, Leonard, "Transformations in the Middle Eastern Subordinate System after 1967, "1971 (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Brown, Cecil H., "Patrilineality or Parallel/Cross? A Structural and Semantic Account of Principal Distinctions in Arab Kinship, "1974 (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - A Chapter in French Colonial Policy and the Emergence of Modern Nationalism, "1970 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Brown, Kenneth, "Profile of a Nineteenth Century Moroccan Scholar, "1971 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - A Nineteenth Century Berber (Tashelhit) Poem, "1972 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Burke, Edmund, III, "The Political Role of the Moroccan Ulama, 1860-1912, "1970 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - A Study of the Tribal Rebellion of 1911, "1973 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Eickelman, Dale F., "Is There an Islamic City? The Making of a Quarter in a Moroccan Town, "1973 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - A Study in Historical Anthropology, "1973 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Speculations on the Setting and Limits of Legal Change, "1971 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Notes on the Balinese Cockfight, "1971 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Towards an Interpretive Theory of Culture, "1972 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Reflections on the Symbolics of Power, "1974 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Geertz, Clifford, "Art as a Cultural System, "1975 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Anthropology 447, Seminar in Theories of Culture, " bibliography, 1970 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - The South `Catches Up, '"1972 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Reflections Based on Field Material from Herat, Northwest Afghanistan, "1972 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Grossman, Joan D., reprint, 1972 (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Halpern, Manfred, "Dialectics of Continuity, Change, Collaboration, Conflict and Justice in Traditional Muslim Societies, " "Bibliography, "1968 (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Harik, Iliya F., "Mobilization Policy and Village Politics, "n.d. (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Harik, Iliya F., "The Impact of the Domestic Market on Rural-Urban Relations, " Working Paper No. 2, International Development Research Center, Indiana University, Bloomington, 1971 (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Hopkins, Nicholas S., "Economic Bases of Social Structure in Testure (Tunisia), "1971 (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - Hörder, Max-Hermann, and Theodor Hanf, reprint, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Human Ecology, McGill University, faculty seminar, 1969-1970 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Before and after Land Reform, "1969 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Khuri, Fuad I., "Two Suburbs of Beirut, "n.d. (Box 26, Folder 4-6)
  - A Stage between Family and National Allegiance, "n.d. (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Loffler, Reinhold, "Charismatic Leadership and Cultural Change in a SW-Iranian Community, "1968 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Mansur, Fatma, "Underdevelopment, Religion and Politics, "1967 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - McCoy, Charles S., reprint, 1964 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Murray, G. W., "The `Ababda, " Survey Department Paper No. 51, Ministry of Finance, Survey of Eygpt, 1951 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Okulov, A. F., "The Features and Significance of Secularisation, "n.d. (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Owen, Wyn F., "Land Use and Land Tenure Policy with a Population Constraint, "1969 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Separate Worlds and Symbolic Shelter, "n.d. (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - A Geographical Perspective, "n.d. (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Premier Festival Culturel PanAfrican, Alger, program, 1969 (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - An Explanation and Some Comparison, "1970 (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Rosen, Lawrence, "Moslem-Jewish Relations in a Moroccan City, "n.d. (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Rosen, Lawrence, "Rural Political Process and National Political Structure in Morocco, "n.d. (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Rosen, Lawrence, "The Social and Conceptual Framework of Arab-Berber Relations in Central Morocco, "1970 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Problems of Personal and Social Choice by Charles Fried, 1970 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Salzman, Philip C., "Multiple Resource Nomadism in Iranian Baluchistan, " American Anthropological Association Meetings, New Orleans, 1969 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Sangree, Walter H., "The Structure and the Symbol Underlying the Choice to Become a Christian in Bantu Tiriki, " C.S.A.S. meeting, Madison, Wisconsin, May 2, 1957 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Schlegel, Stuart A., "Muslim-Christian Conflict in the Philippine South, "n.d. (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Schneider, David M., "Comments to Be Published in a New Edition of Rivers' Kinship and Social Organization (1914), "1965 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Towards a Definition of Kinship, "1969 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Schneider, David M., "Middle Class and Lower Class American Kinship, "n.d. (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Shils, Edward, "Consensus, " International Political Science Association, Brussels, September, 1967 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Shorter, Frederic C., "The Application of Development Hypotheses in Middle Eastern Studies, "n.d. (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Tunisian Private Farms, "1969 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - The Drama of Hussain, "1970 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Violich, Francis, reprint, 1972 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Zonis, Marvin, "Political Elites and Political Cynicism in Iran, "1967 (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - "The Differentiation of Politics and Administration in Some Centralized Kingdom, "n.d. (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - "Some Observations on the Comparative Analysis of Middle Eastern Military Institutions, "n.d. (Box 27, Folder 17)
- Series VI: Africa Research Materials
  Series VI, Africa Research Materials (Boxes 27-44), is divided into seven subseries. The General subseries is composed of correspondence and manuscripts generated by Fallers' participation in the Ford Foundation's Review of African Studies Programs in the United States, the Peace Corps' African Lawyers' Program, and the Washington Center of Foreign Policy Research's Task Force on Africa. Subseries 2, Basutoland, contains material concerning Fallers' participation in the Ford Foundation's Commission on Land Tenure for the government of Basutoland (Lesotho) in 1962-1963.